{   "Test1":
     [ 
        {
            "id": 0,
            "Question": "What was the name of the land bridge that connected Asia and North America?",
            "Answers": ["Beringian Strait", "Atlantic Strait", "Bering Strait", "Pangean Strait"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Bering Strait"
        },

        {
            "id": 1,
            "Question": "What crop was relied on to develop the Western Hemisphere's first settled population?",
            "Answers": ["Corn", "Squash", "Wheat", "Beans"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Corn"
        },

        {
            "id": 2,
            "Question": "What three crops are known as the 'Three Sisters'?",
            "Answers": ["Corn, Wheat, Beans", "Squash, Beans, Carrots", "Squash, Beans, Corn", "Wheat, Squash, Beans"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Squash, Beans, Corn"
        },

        {
            "id": 3,
            "Question": "Define Chiefdom.",
            "Answers": ["A hierarchical, clan-based system that gave leaders both secular and sacred authority",
                        "A non-hierarchical, clan-based system where there is no central authority",
                        "A hierarchical, clan-based system that gave leaders only sacred authority",
                        "A hierarchical, clan based system that gave leaders only secular authority"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "A hierarchical, clan-based system that gave leaders both secular and sacred authority"
        },

        {
            "id": 4,
            "Question": "What were gathering in the Pacific Northwest centered on elaborate feasts called?",
            "Answers": ["Potlucks", "Potlatches", "Potlaches", "Potlacks"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Potlatches"
        },

        {
            "id": 5,
            "Question": "Who were the first Europeans to reach the Americas?",
            "Answers": ["The British", "The Portuguese", "The Spanish", "The Scandinavians"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The Scandinavians"
        },

        {
            "id": 6,
            "Question": "Where did Columnbus and the other explorers land in 1492?",
            "Answers": ["Florida", "The Bahamas", "Brazil", "Guatamala"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The Bahamas"
        },

        {
            "id": 7,
            "Question": "What item did Columbus demand from the Arawaks?",
            "Answers": ["Bronze", "Silver", "Gold", "Diamonds"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Gold"
        },

        {
            "id": 8,
            "Question": "What was the most powerful Native Civilzation ever seen in the Western Hemisphere?",
            "Answers": ["The Aztecs", "The Mayans", "The Incans", "The Cherokee"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The Aztecs"
        },

        {
            "id": 9,
            "Question": "How long did the war between the Spaniards and Aztecs last?",
            "Answers": ["7 months,", "1 year", "2 years", "3 years"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "2 years"
        }
    ],

    "Test2": [
        {
            "id": 0,
            "Question": "What was the Black Legend?",
            "Answers": ["The plague", "Spain's infamous treatment of indegenous people in the Americas", 
                "A decrease in interest in the church", "Portugal's infamous treatment of indegenous people in the Americas"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Spain's infamous treatment of indegenous people in the Americas"
        },

        {
            "id": 1,
            "Question": "What was the fabled Northwest Passage?",
            "Answers": ["A mythical waterway passing through the North American continent to Asia", "A mythical waterway passing through the North American continent to Africa", 
                "A mythical waterway passing through the North American content towards a massive amount of hidden gold", "A mythical waterway passing through the North American continent to a massive amount of hidden silver"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "A mythical waterway passing through the North American continent to Asia"
        },

        {
            "id": 2,
            "Question": "What was the motive of French colonization?",
            "Answers": ["To create permanent settlements", "To expand trading", "To seek gold", "To seek land"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "To expand trading"
        },

        {
            "id": 3,
            "Question": "What were some freedoms the Dutch enjoyed?",
            "Answers": ["Women maintained separate legal identities from their husbands and greater religious tolerance and freedom of the press was embraced", 
                "Slavery was outlawed and greater religious tolerance and freedom of the press was embraced", 
                "Slavery was outlawed and women maintained separate legal identities from their husbands", "Greater religious tolerance and freedom of the press was embraced and lower classes enjoyed more political representation"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Women maintained separate legal identities from their husbands and greater religious tolerance and freedom of the press was embraced"
        },

        {
            "id": 4,
            "Question": "What was at the site of modern-day Wall Street under the Dutch?",
            "Answers": ["A major trading site", "A defensive wall", "Nothing", "A plantation"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "A defensive wall"
        },

        {
            "id": 5,
            "Question": "What modern-day country occupies what Portugal claimed as territory?",
            "Answers": ["Argentina", "Chile", "Brazil", "Venezuela"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Brazil"
        }, 

        {
            "id": 6,
            "Question": "What industries powered early colonial Brazil?",
            "Answers": ["Tobacco and the slave trade", "Sugar and the slave trade", "Extraction of silver", "Extraction of gold"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Sugar and the slave trade"
        },

        {
            "id": 7,
            "Question": "What happened to the Roanoke Colony?",
            "Answers": ["They were killed by local Native Americans", "They intermarried into a local tribe", "It's still unknown", "They died from a famine"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "It's still unknown"
        },

        {
            "id": 8,
            "Question": "What was wrong with where Jamestown was located?",
            "Answers": ["The area was riddled with disease", "The soil was terrible", "The local Native Americans were hostile and the brackish tidal water led to disease", 
                "The soil was terrible and brackish tidal water led to disease"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The soil was terrible and brackish tidal water led to disease"
        },

        {
            "id": 9,
            "Question": "What items did the Powhatan want?",
            "Answers": ["Chickens, tools, and guns", "Kettles, tools, and horses", "Guns, metal ax-heads, and kettles", "Metal ax-heads, kettles, tools and guns"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Metal ax-heads, kettles, tools and guns"
        }

    ],
    "Test3": [

        {
            "id": 0,
            "Question": "Which nation lost New York and then briefly reconquered it in 1667?",
            "Answers": ["Spain", "The Netherlands", "France", "Sweden"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The Netherlands"
        },

        {
            "id": 1,
            "Question": "Carolina could be called 'a colony of a colony'. What was the colony in question?",
            "Answers": ["Haiti", "Jamaica", "Brazil", "Barbados"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Barbados"
        },

        {
            "id": 2,
            "Question": "What incentives were offered for people to settle in Carolina?",
            "Answers": ["Large land grant and religious freedom", "Religious tolerance, political representation by assembly, excemption from fees, and large land grants", 
                "Criminals were offered indentured servitude over other punishments", "Political representation by assembly and large land grants"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Religious tolerance, political representation by assembly, excemption from fees, and large land grants"
        },

        {
            "id": 3,
            "Question": "Why was North Carolina founded as a separate province?",
            "Answers": ["This region was resistent to the Carolina authority", "The North and South built their economies around different crops",
                "There was conflict within the Carolina authority that caused a split", "There is no significant reason"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "This region was resistent to the Carolina authority"
        },

        {
            "id": 4,
            "Question": "What was the Glorious Revolution?",
            "Answers": ["The overthrowing of Charles II over his Protestant and pro-French policies", 
                "The overthrowing of William of Holland over his Protestant and pro-Spain policies", "The overthrowing of James II over his Catholic and pro-French policies", 
                "The overthrowing of William of Holland over his Catholic and pro-French policies"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The overthrowing of James II over his Catholic and pro-French policies"
        },

        {
            "id": 5,
            "Question": "What colonies were in the Dominion of New England?",
            "Answers": ["Virginia and the New England colonies", "The New England colonies", "The New England colonies and North Carolina", "The New England colonies, New York, and New Jersey"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The New England colonies, New York, and New Jersey"
        },

        {
            "id": 6,
            "Question": "What did the rebels of Bacon's Rebellion want?",
            "Answers": ["To expand westward for more land", "Lower taxes", "More political representation", "Larger land grants for newly freed servants and slaves"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "To expand westward for more land"
        },

        {
            "id": 7,
            "Question": "Who was Metacom?",
            "Answers": ["A Wampanoag sachem who led the efforts against Puritan expansion", "A Pequot sachem who led the efforts against Puritan expansion", 
                "A Mohegan sachem who sought to ally with the Puritans", "A Wamanoag sachem who sought to ally with the Puritans"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "A Wampanoag sachem who led the efforts against Puritan expansion"
        },

        {
            "id": 8,
            "Question": "What started the Susquehannock War?",
            "Answers": ["The colonists expanding westerard into Susquehannock territory", "The accidental killing of Susquehannock people", "The Susquehannock acted on increasingly feeling a loss in the balance of power",
                "A group of rebels went into Susquehannock territory looking for conflict"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "The accidental killing of Susquehannock people"
        },

        {
            "id": 9,
            "Question": "What did Sarah Drummond, the wife of a rebel leader, advocate?",
            "Answers": ["More religious tolerance in the Virginia colony", "Political representation for those with no land", 
                "Independence from England", "Further westward expansion"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Independence from England"
        }
    ],

    "Test4": [
        
        {
            "id": 0,
            "Question": "Early on in Virginia, ___ could be exchanged for notes that could be traded as money.",
            "Answers": ["Silver", "Gold", "Tobacco", "Sugar"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Tobacco"
        },
        
        {
            "id": 1,
            "Question": "Which colony became the first place in the Western World to issue paper bills as money?",
            "Answers": ["New York", "Virginia", "North Carolinia", "Massachusetts"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Massachusetts"
        },

        {
            "id": 2,
            "Question": "One in ___ coloninists lived in cities by 1775.",
            "Answers": ["Twenty", "Ten", "Thirty", "Fifty"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Twenty"
        },

        {
            "id": 3,
            "Question": "In 1750, which colony had a majority enslaved African population?",
            "Answers": ["North Carolina", "South Carolina", "Virginia", "Georgia"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "South Carolina"
        },

        {
            "id": 4,
            "Question": "In which colonies did slavery never take off as a system of labor?",
            "Answers": ["Massachusetts, Connecticut, New Hampshire", "New York, New Jersey, Massachusetts", "New Jersey, Connecticut, Massachusetts",
            "New York, Connecticut, New Hampshire"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Massachusetts, Connecticut, New Hampshire"
        },

        {
            "id": 5,
            "Question": "Which colonies were proprietary colonies?",
            "Answers": ["Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and Delaware", "New york, New Hampshire, and Delaware", "Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Connecticut, and Delaware",
            "Pennsylvania, Delaware, New Jersey, and Maryland"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Pennsylvania, Delaware, New Jersey, and Maryland"
        },

        {
            "id": 6,
            "Question": "Which type of colony was most tightly controlled by the crown?",
            "Answers": ["Provincial", "Propietary", "Charter", "All were equally controlled by the crown"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Provincial"
        },

        {
            "id": 7,
            "Question": "Which type of colony involved property-owning men electing the governors?",
            "Answers": ["Provincial", "Propietary", "Charter", "All governors were appointed by the crown"],
            "CorrectAnswer": "Charter"
        },

        {
            "id": 8,
            "Question": "Define social contract.",
            "Answers": ["It's the idea that government is put in place by the people", "It's the idea that government is put in place by god",
            "It's the idea that government is put in place by a few wealthy elite.", "It's the idea that government is put in place by a few intellectuals."],
            "CorrectAnswer": "It's the idea that government is put in place by the people."
        }
    ]
}